Angshuman Mazumdar

I believe that engineering and art go hand-in-hand. I am also an ardent follower of interactive media, especially video games, because I believe that they provide a great platform for experiences to flourish, and ideas to be communicated through stories that leave a lasting impression in our minds.





angshuman.mazumdar@gmail.com



🙎 West Lafayette, Indiana



https://binaryvectorjr.github.io/portfolio

(585) 406-9165



in https://www.linkedin.com/in/angshuman-mazumdar-a0b75a130/

EDUCATION

Master of Science (Computer Graphics Technology)

Purdue University, West Lafayette (Indiana) August 2019 – Expected May 2021 (GPA – 3.97)

Capstone Project

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester (New York) January 2019 – May 2019

Bachelor of Technology (Electronics and Communication)

Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore 2015 - 2019 (CGPA - 8.69)

High School and Senior School

Don Bosco Senior Secondary School, Guwahati 2003 - 2015 (93.4%)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Purdue University 08/2020 - Present West Lafayette (IN, USA)

• Responsible for assisting students with learning NX 12.0, for the course "Graphical Communication and Spatial Analysis"

Supporter

The Power of Connection (Documentary) 05/2020 - 12/2020 West Lafayette (IN, USA)

Graphic Designer

MOX - Movement of Expression 02/2018 - 08/2019 Shillong, India

Trainee

Bharti Airtel 05/2018 - 06/2018 Chandigarh, India

• Summer internship. Helped in streamlining the pipeline for form data collection and organization through VBA in Microsoft Excel which reduced the time for data retrieval and organization

ACHIEVEMENTS

Design Advisor for Team Vimaanas (01/2017 - 06/2018) Team Vimaanas is the official Micro-Class RC Aviation team of VIT.

Design Head (BEAM-VIT) (06/2016 - 05/2017)

BEAM-VIT was a club of VIT University. Also held the position of Design Co-Chair for BIDSF 2017. BIDSF is an annual event organized by the Biotech Division of VIT.

SOFTWARE FAMILIARITY

Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator Adobe Premiere Pro Adobe After Effects Unreal Engine 4 Unity3D World Machine Houdini Autodesk Maya Autodesk 3DS Max Blender Trimble SketchUp NX 12.0 HTML and CSS

C++ and C#

Microsoft Office Suite (PowerPoint, Word, Excel)

MAJOR PROJECTS

Walking in a Crowd Full of Virtual Characters: Effects of Virtual Character Appearance on Human Movement Behavior (09/2019 - 01/2020)

- Paper on effects of a virtual crowd with varied appearance
- Focused on the relation between human movement in such virtual crowds
- Targeted towards future crowd-based studies and scenarios

Embodiment for the Difference: A VR Experience of Bipolar **Disorder** (08/2019 – 12/2019)

- The objective was to develop a simulation in virtual reality to provide an experience of the effects of Bipolar Disorder; shed light on a few of the challenges a person suffering from bipolar disorder would have to face in their lives
- Platform used for delivering experience was Oculus Quest

Parkinson's Disease Assist Device using Machine Learning and Internet of Things (07/2017 - 04/2018)

- Project focused on development of a prototype of a spoon which senses the hand motion of an individual suffering from Parkinson's disease.
- Basic idea was to provide counter motion to the trembling actions of a patient's hand, to minimize spills

LANGUAGES

Native Language Assamese **English** Full working proficiency Hindi **Bilingual Proficiency** French Novice